A Guide to the Amaza Lee Meredith Papers, 1912, 1930-1938
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
- SERIES V: ORGANIZATIONAL AFFILIATIONS
  - C. Virginia Federation of Colored Women's Clubs
    - Meredith-Printed Personal Virginia Federation of Colored Women's Clubs n.d. (Box-folder 12:172)
- SERIES VI. SCRAPBOOKS
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:173)
  - Scrapbook n.d. (Box-folder 13:174)
  - Scrapbook- Family News Clippings n.d. (Box-folder 13:175)
  - Scrapbook- Family Coat of arms n.d. (Box-folder 13:176)
  - Scrapbook- Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:177)
  - Scrapbook- Family-Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:178)
  - Scrapbook- Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:179)
  - Scrapbook- Residence Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:180)
  - Scrapbook- Family n.d. (Box-folder 13:181)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:182)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:183)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:184)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:185)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:186)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:187)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:188)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:189)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:190)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:191)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photograph n.d. (Box-folder 13:192)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:193)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:194)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:195)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 13:196)
  - Scrapbook-Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:197)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:198)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:199)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:200)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:201)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:202)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:203)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:204)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:205)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:206)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:207)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:208)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:209)
  - Scrapbook - Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:210)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:211)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:212)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:213)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:214)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:215)
  - Scrapbook - Family Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:216)
  - Scrapbook n.d. (Box-folder 14:217)
  - Scrapbook n.d. (Box-folder 14:218)
  - Scrapbook - Personal Photographs n.d. (Box-folder 14:219)
  - Scrapbook - Kersey Speech n.d. (Box-folder 14:220)
  - Scrapbook - NAACP Membership Certificate n.d. (Box-folder 14:221)
  - Scrapbook- Richards n.d. (Box-folder 14:222)
  - Scrapbook - Meredith (Personal) n.d. (Box-folder 14:223)
  - Scrapbook- Scrapbook - Report on Unrest at Kent State by Iris Richards n.d. (Box-folder 14:224)
  - Scrapbook - Meredith Historiography 1915 & A. S. 1940 (Box-folder 14:225)
  - Scrapbook entitled "Photograph", 7.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    This is a collection of cards and programs. Included in this scrapbook is one of several telegrams.
  - Untitled scrapbook n.d., 6.5 x 10 inches (Box 15)
    This is a photographic record of Azurest South during its construction and as the home shared by Amaza Meredith and Edna Colson.
  - Scrapbook #1: Untitled n.d., 12.5 x 10 inches (Box 15)
    Correspondence, number of letters concerning Amamza Meredith teaching career in Lynchburg, and her being recruited to come to Virginia State by John M. Gandy. The other letters are mainly from friends concerning a variety of subjects. Included in the scrapbook is numerous of news-clippings, programs, tickets and other items collected by her long life.
  - Scrapbook #2: Art n.d., 10.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    Some correspondence, most of the materials consist of several programs, which were designed by Miss Meredith. Included in this book are also a number of speeches most concerning the teaching of or about art.
  - Scrapbook #3: Photographs n.d., 11 x 12 inches (Box 15)
    A collection of photographs covering a wide area.
  - Scrapbook #4: Poems n.d., 10 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    This scrapbook includes a number of poems and letters written by Amaza Lee Meredith. The Evening song and Alma Mater of Virginia State is embodied in this scrapbook. Other letters and poems written or given to Miss Meredith can also be found. There are newspaper-clippings of poems written by Miss Amaza and also others that she collected.
  - Scrapbook #5: My Children n.d., 10.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    Correspondence, photo's and newspaper-clippings from some of her former students. Included in this scrapbook are: James Gault Chander Flymn, Roderick Taylor, Freddrick F. Kersy, Reyenea Perry, Mildred Fountain, Huedillard Fitzgerald. Stanford Evens and others. There is addition some material about Lynchberg Virginia.
  - Scrapbook # 6: A L 1895-19 -, 11.5 x 11 inches (Box 15)
    Some correspondence, news-clipping, programs most of which document the establishment of the Meredith Art at Virginia State in 1972 Gallery.
  - Scrapbook #7: "Miss Anne" n.d., 9.5 x 11.5 (Box 15)
    This scrapbook contains some correspondence, programs and printed articles about Anne Spencer of Lynchburg. Mrs. Spencer was a poet of the Harlem Renaissance Period. One of Miss Meredith sisters was married to Miss Spencer sons.
  - Scrapbook #8: Letters 1941-1976 (Box 15)
    A Scrapbook of letters from a wide group of people dating from 1941 through 1976.
  - Scrapbook #9: Dr. I and Fred III 1980-1982 (Box 15)
    Some correspondence photographs and cards of sympathy about the death of Iris Terry Richards. Dr. Richards was Miss Meredith niece.
  - Scrapbook #10: Untitled n.d., 10.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    News-clippings, newsletters and other material mostly about Art.
  - Scrapbook #11: Honors n.d., 10 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    A combination of items includes Miss Meredith's High School grades and diploma. There are letters of recognition and certificates.
  - Scrapbook #12: Cards n.d., 10.5 x 11.5 inches (Box 15)
    Most of the material document Miss Meredith involvement with the Gillfield Baptist Church in Petersburg, Va.
  - Scrapbook # 13: Amaza Lee Meredith September 1, 1958 (Box 15)
    This scrapbook document Miss Meredith retirement from Virginia State University in 1958. There are cards, programs, letters and photographs.
- SERIES VII. PHOTOS -- LOOSE
  - Aunt Bea, Miss Meredith 1980's (Box-folder 16:226)
  - Eleanor (4 years) & Phalix (2 years) 1926 (Box-folder 16:227)
  - Angie Nicholas 1930 (Box-folder 16:228)
  - Chaucey Spencer 1939 (Box-folder 16:229)
  - Stafford Evans 1940's (Box-folder 16:230)
  - Mary Moore 1942 (Box-folder 16:231)
  - (Box-folder 16:)
  - Stafford Evans 1943 (Box-folder 16:232)
  - Wayne 1960 (Box-folder 16:233)
  - Wm. Earl Brooks 6-6-61 (Box-folder 16:234)
  - Wayne, Mike 1961 (Box-folder 16:235)
  - Wayne 1961 or 1962 (Box-folder 16:236)
  - Mike 1962 (Box-folder 16:237)
  - Hattie Pearl Hilliard 1-25-64 (Box-folder 16:238)
  - Hattie Pearl in Huston 12/1964 (Box-folder 16:239)
  - Betty Blackburn 5/1965 (Box-folder 16:240)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Thadeus Boardman 11/13/65 (Box-folder 16:241)
  - Hitomi Young 1967 (Box-folder 16:242)
  - Hitomi and Warren Matthews 9/12/70 (Box-folder 16:243)
  - Hattie Pearl, others 1970's (Box-folder 16:244)
  - Mike 1971 (Box-folder 16:245)
  - Wayne 1971 (Box-folder 16:246)
  - Wayne 1972 (Box-folder 16:247)
  - Wayne 1972 (Box-folder 16:248)
  - 1972 Wayne (Box-folder 16:249)
  - Wayne 1972 (Box-folder 16:250)
  - Dr. Colson, Miss Meredith 1973 (Box-folder 16:251)
  - Andre Wadlington 3/74 (Box-folder 16:252)
  - Orlando Dodson 1974 (Box-folder 16:253)
  - Randy Stevens 3/1/75 (Box-folder 16:254)
  - Wayne A. Stevens 3/3/75 (Box-folder 16:255)
  - Melanie Hillard, Andrea Waddlington, Teri Dawn 12/28/75 (Box-folder 16:256)
  - Dr. E. Colson, Nurse Gracie Pollard 8/8/78 (Box-folder 16:257)
  - Dr. Colson 8/8/78 (Box-folder 16:258)
  - Maisha 1979 (1 yr. Old) (Box-folder 16:259)
  - Brenda Richards, Evelyn, Hempstead, N.Y. 5/29/80 (Box-folder 16:260)
  - Miss Amaza Meredith, Brenda Richards, Hempstead, N.Y. 5/29/80 (Box-folder 16:261)
  - Miss Meredith, S. Evan's daughter, Azurest South 8/12/80 (Box-folder 16:262)
  - Miss Meredith, S. Evans daughter, Azurest South 8/12/80 (Box-folder 16:263)
  - Miss Meredith 7/81 (Box-folder 16:264)
  - Myra Ball, Wilfred Ball n.d. (Box-folder 16:265)
  - Cornelia Brent n.d. (Box-folder 16:266)
  - James Brent Jr. n.d. (Box-folder 16:267)
  - Shirley, Clearence, Michele, Clearnecne IV, Jennifer n.d. (Box-folder 16:268)
  - The Dabneys n.d. (Box-folder 16:269)
  - Stafford Evans during WWII n.d. (Box-folder 16:270)
  - Stafford Evans n.d. (Box-folder 16:271)
  - Shirley Goode n.d. (Box-folder 16:272)
  - Meredith (Landscape) n.d. (Box-folder 16:273)
  - Miss Meredith n.d. (Box-folder 16:274)
  - Gayle Minnis n.d. (Box-folder 16:275)
  - Angelita Nicholas, Lestrita Nicholas n.d. (Box-folder 16:276)
  - Lestria Nicholas, Angelitca Nicholas n.d. (Box-folder 16:277)
  - Lestria Nicholas, Angelita Nicholas n.d. (Box-folder 16:278)
  - John Scott n.d. (Box-folder 16:279)
  - Wayne Stevens n.d. (Box-folder 16:280)
  - The Walter Pidely Family Christmas n.d. (Box-folder 16:281)
  - The Pidelys n.d. (Box-folder 16:282)
  - Elton Willis (6 yr. old) n.d. (Box-folder 16:283)
  - Grace Willis n.d. (Box-folder 16:284)
  - Ann Critendon, Preston Prairie View Texas 1965 (Box-folder 16:285)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas- Photos from Anne and Dot n.d. (Box-folder 16:286)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas- Andot n.d. (Box-folder 16:287)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas- Dog named Sherrie and Flower n.d. (Box-folder 16:288)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas 1965 (Box-folder 16:289)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas 1965 (Box-folder 16:290)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas - ducks 1965 (Box-folder 16:291)
  - Ann Critendon Preston, Prairie View Texas 1965 (Box-folder 16:292)
  - Ann Critendon Preston Prairie View Texas- Andot 8/16/57 (Box-folder 16:293)
  - Azurest South 6-2-26-28 (Box-folder 16:294)
  - Azurest South n.d. (Box-folder 16:295)
  - Azurest South n.d. (Box-folder 16:296)
  - Azurest South Dining Room n.d. (Box-folder 16:297)
  - Azurest South- Snow Winter -Furniture n.d. (Box-folder 16:298)
  - Azurest South, Dr. Colson, Miss Meredith, Nurse Pollard 7/78 (Box-folder 16:299)
  - Azurest South 1980 (Box-folder 16:300)
  - Azurest South 1980 (Box-folder 16:301)
  - Azurest South- Flowers n.d. (Box-folder 16:302)
  - Azurest South- Flowers Landscape n.d. (Box-folder 16:303)
  - Azurest n.d. (Box-folder 16:304)
  - Azurest South n.d. (Box-folder 16:305)
  - Azurest North n.d. (Box-folder 16:306)
  - Ann Spencer- Lynchburg,Va. Spencer Home n.d. (Box-folder 16:307)
  - Ann Spencer- Lynchburg, Va., Spencer Home n.d. (Box-folder 16:308)
  - Home - Lynchburg n.d. (Box-folder 16:309)
  - Anne Spencer Home n.d. (Box-folder 16:310)
  - Unidentified 1955 (Box-folder 16:311)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:312)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:313)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:314)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:315)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:316)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:317)
  - Unidentified n.d. (Box-folder 16:318)
- SERIES VIII. PRINTED (Box 17)
- SERIES IX. BLUE PRINTS, LINE DRAWINGS (Box 18)
- SERIES X. OVERSIZED (Box 18)